A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Office of the Arts, Program Files FA640
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Office of the Arts, Program Files
1956-1983
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA640
85.2 Cubic Feet
Includes 3 non-standard size boxes and 3 document boxes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in 16 series primarily by file type.
Scope and Contents
Includes but not limited to: program files, grant and grantee files, survey files, comptroller and consultant reports, Edward D'Arms interview notes, reference materials and statistical data.
Ford Foundation
- Administrative Interns Program, 1961-1973; I
  Related Materials
  See also: Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), 06200406 (PA62-406): PROGRAM FOR ADMINISTRATIVE INTERNS (Reel 2561 through 2568).
  - Program for Administrative Interns -- Correspondence (A), 1961-1970 (Box 1)
  - Program for Administrative Interns -- Correspondence (B-C), 1961-1972 (Box 1)
  - Program for Administrative Interns -- Correspondence (D-J), 1961-1970 (Box 1)
  - Program for Administrative Interns -- Correspondence (K-M), 1961-1970 (Box 1)
  - Program for Administrative Interns -- Correspondence (N-R), 1961-1971 (Box 1)
  - Program for Administrative Interns -- Correspondence (S-Z), 1961-1971 (Box 2)
  - Program for Administrative Interns -- Correspondence (A-Z) (25 folders), 1961-1972 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Press Releases, 1964-1969 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- References, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Statistics, 1961-1969 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Status Reports, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Timetables, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Training Situations, [1968] (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Evaluation (Consultants), 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Evaluation -- Evaluation Correspondence (Candidates), 1973 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Evaluation -- Program Background, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Evaluation -- Program Budget, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Evaluation -- Nominees, 1963-1969 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Background, 1961-1970 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Evaluation, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Field Director, 1962-1969 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Forms, 1961-1965 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Forms, 1966-1970 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Grant Actions, 1962-1971 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Apr 5, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, May 16-17, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, May 23-24, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, May 1-2, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Jun 1-2, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Apr 29-30, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Jun 1, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Apr 28-29, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Administrative Interns Program meeting recording, 1966 April 28-29 (Box 72, Reel AV 6303)
      Scope and Contents
      Place: Ford Foundation offices. Present: Thomas C. Fichandler, Howard Harrington, Peter Zeisler, Michael Mabry, and Marcia Thompson.
      Access Restrictions
      RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order.
    - Administrative Interns Program meeting recording, 1966 April 29 (Box 72, Reel AV 6304)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Jun 3, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Administrative Interns Program meeting recording, 1966 June 3 (Box 72, Reel AV 6305)
    - Administrative Interns Program meeting recording, 1966 June 3 (Box 72, Reel AV 6306)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Apr 4-5, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Nominees Material, 1967 April 4-5 (Reel 9326)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, May 2, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Apr 8-9, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Nominees Material, 1968 April 8-9 (Reel 9327; 9328; 9329)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, May 6, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Apr 7-8, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, Nominees Material, 1969 April 7 (Reel 9330; 9331; 9332; 9333)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Meeting, May 7, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges First Year, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Second Year, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Third Year, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Fourth Year, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Fifth Year, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Sixth Year, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Seventh Year, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Judges Eighth Year, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominators' Correspondence, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Administrative Interns Program -- Nominees' Correspondence, 1969 (Box 3)
- Budget Files, 1970-1983; II
  - Budget, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Budget, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Budget, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Proposed Budget Fiscal Year 1973, Jun 1972 (Box 4)
  - Budget Papers, 1973-1975 (Box 4)
  - Proposed Budget Fiscal Years 1974-1975, Jun 1973 (Box 4)
  - Budget Papers, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Budget Papers, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Proposed Budget Fiscal Years 1975-1977, Mar 1975 (Box 4)
  - Budget Papers, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Proposed Budget Fiscal Years 1976-1977, Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Budget Papers, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Budget Papers, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Budget Papers, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Office of Arts Program Budget, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Office of Arts Program Budget, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
- Management Costs, 1958-1981; III
  - Management Costs/Proposed Budget Fiscal Year 1958-Fiscal Year 1981 (24 folders), 1958-1981 (Box 5)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Budget Book FY1964-1981 (Box 5)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Fiscal Status Report, Feb 1968-Sep 1981 (Box 5)
- Comptroller's Reports, 1959-1981; IV
  - Comptroller's Reports, 1959-1973 (Box 6)
  - Comptroller's Reports, 1974-1977 (Box 6)
  - Comptroller's Reports, 1978-1991 (Box 6)
- Edward F. D'Arms Interview Notes, 1958-1969; V
  Includes Edward F. D’Arms’s handwritten notes from interviews of prominent figures in dance, music, theater and the visual arts. Also includes correspondence with interviewees, and printed ephemera collected from arts organizations.
  - Interview Notes, 1958-1959 (Box 6)
  - Interview Notes, 1960-1961 (Box 6)
  - Interview Notes, 1962 (Box 6)
    Includes a proposal from photographer Ralph Steiner (1899-1986) for a “new kind of center for creative photography in New York City”.
  - Interview Notes, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Interview Notes, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Interview Notes, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - Interview Notes, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
- Performing Arts Survey Files, 1956-1978; VI
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Totals, Averages, Percentages, Growth Rates, Feb 11, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Growth Rates, Mar 3, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Totals by Organization, Jun 9, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Percentages by Organization (1/2), Jun 9, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Percentages by Organization (2/2), Jun 9, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Totals, Averages and Percentages -- By Art Type/Size Class, Mar 14, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Totals, Growth Rates, Averages and Percentages -- By Art Type/Size Class, Jun 9, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Totals Report -- By Organization -- Final, Sep 15, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Performing Arts Survey -- Totals, Averages and Percentages -- Art Form, By Class Size -- Final, Sep 15, 1973 (Box 8)
  - ID Numbers Assigned to Respondents (Box 8)
  - Eric Marder Survey, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Organizations in 1971-1974 Survey -- General (Box 8)
  - Memoranda and Letters re: Economic Survey, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Treatment of Specific Line Items, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Data Treatment/Definitions, 1972 (Box 8)
  - National Research Center of the Arts, Inc. (Joe Farrell), 1974 (Box 8)
  - Information Required for Duplicating and Explaining Tapes, 1977 (Box 8)
  - New York Theater Study -- Mathematica, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Alley Theater Study, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Organizations Surveyed, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
  - All Payment Information, 1965-1974 (Box 8)
  - Introduction to Economic Analysis -- Revision 1, May 15-16, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Growth Rates/Constant Dollars, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Economic Survey -- Long Term Trends, undated (Box 8)
  - Distribution of Volumes I and II, 1974 (Box 8)
  - DAP Documentation, 1974 (Box 8)
  - University Presses Program -- Summaries for Expenditures and Allocations, [1961] (Box 10)
  - University Presses Program -- Statistics, 1958-1961 (Box 10)
  - University Presses Program -- Forms, 1962 (Box 10)
  - University Presses Program -- Grant Actions, 1962 (Box 10)
  - University Presses Program -- Press Releases, 1961 (Box 10)
  - University Presses Program -- Evaluation, 1956-1967 (Box 10)
  - Recording/Publication Program -- Forms and Form Letters, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program -- Report Forms, 1966-1976 (Box 10)
  - Concert Artists Program, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Concert Artists Program -- Forms and Form Letters, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Grant Program -- Fact Sheets, Etc., 1963-1965 (Box 10)
  - Independent Schools, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Economic and Financial Survey -- Forms, 1971-1975 (Box 10)
  - (New) American Plays Program, 1976-1978 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Programs -- Forms and Letters, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Survey Procedures Manual -- Performing Arts Survey, 1974-1975 (Box 14)
  - Drafts of Book -- Survey of 166 Professional Nonprofit Theatres, Operas, Symphonies, Ballets and Dance Companies (1/2), 1974 (Box 14)
  - Drafts of Book -- Survey of 166 Professional Nonprofit Theatres, Operas, Symphonies, Ballets and Dance Companies (2/2), 1974 (Box 14)
  - Survey of 166 Professional Nonprofit Theatres, Operas, Symphonies, Ballets and Dance Companies -- Comments on Draft Volumes I and II, 1974 (Box 14)
  - W. McNeil Lowry Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 14)
  - W. McNeil Lowry Correspondence and Book Drafts (1/2), 1974 (Box 14)
  - W. McNeil Lowry Correspondence and Book Drafts (2/2), 1974 (Box 14)
  - W. McNeil Lowry Correspondence -- Economic Survey of Performing Arts Organizations (including reports and data), 1974 (Box 14)
  - Missing Value Estimation Procedure/Raw Data Used by Madansky to Make Calculations (1/2), 1973 (Box 14)
  - Missing Value Estimation Procedure/Raw Data Used by Madansky to Make Calculations (2/2), 1973 (Box 14)
  - "Performing Arts Survey System" Report and related reports re: Economic Survey, 1972 (Box 14)
  - Chattanooga Opera Association (PA70-624), 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Cincinnati Ballet Company (70-624), 1975 (Box 16)
  - Corpus Christi Symphony Orchestra (PA70-624), 1971 (Box 16)
  - Dance Theatre of Harlem (PA70-624), 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Denver Lyric Opera, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Dayton Opera Association, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Des Moines Symphony Association, 1975 (Box 16)
  - First Chamber Dance Company, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Flint Symphony, 1970-1975 (Box 16)
  - Florida Gulf Coast Symphony, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Long Beach Symphony Association, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Madison Civic Music Association, 1975 (Box 16)
  - Midland-Odessa Symphony and Chorale, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Minnesota Dance Theatre and School, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Negro Ensemble Company, 1971 (Box 16)
  - New Jersey State Opera, 1971 (Box 16)
  - New Jersey Symphony Orchestra, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Old Globe Theatre, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Puerto Rico Symphony Orchestra, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Roundabout Theater, 1971 (Box 16)
  - St. Louis Opera, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Savannah Symphony Orchestra, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Syracuse Stage, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Toledo Opera Association (Box 16)
  - Tri-cities Opera Company, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Tulsa Opera (Box 16)
  - Utica Symphony Orchestra, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Wolf Trap Foundation (Box 16)
  - Performing Arts Survey Reading File, 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Guy Herregat's Simulation Models -- #1, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Guy Herregat's Simulation Models -- #2, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Guy Herregat's Simulation Models -- Spearman Ranks Order Correlations, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Guy Herregat's Simulation Models -- Changes for Hard and Plugged Data, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Guy Herregat's Simulation Models -- Regressions, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Guy Herregat's Simulation Models -- Analysis of Covariance, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Tables Used in Volume I of Financial Survey of the Performing Arts, 1974 (Box 16)
  - Performing Arts Survey Files - Ballet Training, 1973 and undated; VI.1
    - Survey -- Ballet Training Resources in the United States -- Alabama-Florida (59-234) (Box 9)
    - Survey -- Ballet Training Resources in the United States -- Georgia-Michigan (59-234) (Box 9)
    - Survey -- Ballet Training Resources in the United States -- Minnesota-Oregon (59-234) (Box 9)
    - Survey -- Ballet Training Resources in the United States -- Pennsylvania-Wyoming (59-234) (Box 9)
    - Survey -- Ballet Scholarship Program, 1973 (Box 9)
    - School of American Ballet -- Reports/Evaluations/Questionnaires, 1973 (Box 9)
    - School of American Ballet -- Conference/Evaluation, Apr 27, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Performing Arts Survey Files - Fishman Regressions Runs at Yale, 1973; VI.2
    - Growth Rate Report -- Final, Dec 3, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Fishman Regressions Runs at Yale (1/3), undated (Box 11)
    - Fishman Regressions Runs at Yale (2/3), undated (Box 11)
    - Fishman Regressions Runs at Yale (3/3), undated (Box 11)
    - George and Al's Statistical Model, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Economic Survey -- Madansky Memoranda, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Performing Arts Survey Files - Printouts, 1974, 1976-1977; VI.3
    - Final Tape, Dec 7, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Selected Expanded PAS Tape, Dec 17, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Percentage Tape, Dec 16, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Total Income -- All Organizations, Aug 1, 1977 (Box 12)
    - Total Expenditures -- All Organizations, Aug 1, 1977 (Box 12)
    - All Organizations -- 6 Years, 1965-1971 (Box 13)
    - Individual Selected Organizations, 1965-1974 (Box 13)
    - Selected Organizations -- 6 Years, 1965-1971 (Box 13)
    - All Organizations -- 9 Years, 1965-1974 (Box 13)
    - Selected Organizations -- 9 Years, 1965-1974 (Box 13)
  - Performing Arts Survey - R C Sheldon, 1970-1974; VI.4
    - RC Sheldon Survey Chronological Correspondence, 1970 (Box 15)
    - RC Sheldon Survey Chronological Correspondence, 1971 (Box 15)
    - RC Sheldon Survey Chronological Correspondence, 1972 (Box 15)
    - RC Sheldon Survey Chronological Correspondence, 1973 (Box 15)
    - RC Sheldon Survey Chronological Correspondence, 1974 (Box 15)
    - Ford Foundation Economic Survey Conference Transcripts (1/4), 1971-1972 (Box 15)
    - Ford Foundation Economic Survey Conference Transcripts (2/4), 1972 (Box 15)
    - Ford Foundation Economic Survey Conference Transcripts (3/4), 1972-1973 (Box 15)
    - Ford Foundation Economic Survey Conference Transcripts (4/4), 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Performing Arts Survey - Don Foster Notes, 1971-1973; VI.5
    - Don Foster Notes -- Computer Notes and Changes, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Survey Schedule, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Survey Returns, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Survey Progress Report, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Survey, Aug 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Survey -- New York, Aug 30-Sep 2, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Survey -- New York, Sep 13-17, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Survey, Sep 27-Oct 1, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Budget, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Reviews, 1970-1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Computer Check, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 17)
    - Don Foster Notes -- Miscellaneous, c.1973 (Box 17)
  - Performing Arts Survey - Data/Computer Runs, 1971-1973; VI.6
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Hoffman Runs (1/4), 1971-1972 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Hoffman Runs (2/4), 1971-1972 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Hoffman Runs (3/4), 1971-1972 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Hoffman Runs (4/4), 1971-1972 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Hoffman Runs, 1972 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Analysis Worksheets, 1974 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Clean Organizations (1/2), 1972 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Clean Organizations (2/2), 1972 (Box 18)
    - Performing Arts Survey -- Interim Growth Rates, 1973 (Box 18)
- Stabilization Program, 1971-1983; VII
  - Alley Theatre -- Cash Reserve Program, 1972-1978 (Box 19)
  - Alliance Theatre Company, 1974-1979 (Box 19)
  - Berkshire Theatre Festival, 1973 (Box 19)
  - Boston Ballet (72-11), 1976-1983 (Box 19)
  - Central City Opera House Association, 1971-1977 (Box 19)
  - Children's Theatre Co. (Minneapolis), 1977-1979 (Box 19)
  - Cincinnati Ballet Company, 1971-1979 (Box 19)
  - Greater Miami Opera Association, 1970-1976 (Box 19)
  - Hartford Ballet, 1974-1976 (Box 19)
- Consultant Reports, 1960-1981; VIII
  - Bass, George H. -- Minority Theatre in the US, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Beck, Deborah -- Living Stage Evaluation, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Beglarian, Grant -- Kodaly Musical Training Center, 1970 (Box 20)
  - Blumenfield, F. Yorick -- Reports re: Eastern Europe (1/2), 1969-1972 (Box 20)
  - Blumenfield, F. Yorick -- Reports re: Eastern Europe and China (2/2), 1967-1974 (Box 20)
  - Cantor, Jay -- Artists and Galleries, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Cantor, Jay -- Visual Artists Report -- Artist Files (1/4), 1971 (Box 20)
  - Cantor, Jay -- Visual Artists Report -- Artist Files (2/4), 1971 (Box 20)
  - Cantor, Jay -- Visual Artists Report -- Artist Files (3/4), 1971 (Box 20)
  - Cantor, Jay -- Visual Artists Report -- Artist Files (4/4), 1971 (Box 20)
  - Chapin, Ted, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Cisek, Richard -- African American Participation in Symphony Orchestras, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Clark, Richard C. -- Opera, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Cole, Frederick -- Resources of Research Libraries, Dec 1964 (Box 20)
  - Cole, R. Taylor -- "American Studies Abroad, With Particular Reference to the Council of Learned Societies Program", 1969 (Box 20)
  - D'Arms, Edward -- Visits to Rome, NY; Elyria, OH; and Owensboro, KY, 1976 (Box 20)
  - Austria -- Situation of the Composer, 1963 (Box 21)
  - France -- Position of the Novelist in France, 1960 (Box 21)
  - France -- the Actor and the Playwright, 1965 (Box 21)
  - France -- Situation of the Theater, Opera and Symphony (Box 21)
  - Germany -- The Situation of the Theatre, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Germany -- Theatre in Germany, Dec 1967 (Box 21)
  - Holland -- Music in Holland, Dec 1966 (Box 21)
  - International Council of Museums (ICOM) Studies -- Summary, 1974 (Box 21)
  - International Council of Museums -- Cross-reference Sheets, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Italy -- Music Situation in Italy, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Italy -- The Situation of the Theater, Oct 1966 (Box 21)
  - Portugal -- Situation of Music, the Theater and the Plastic Arts, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Preface -- Draft Copy, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Report Manuscript (French), 1973 (Box 21)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby -- Since 1970 -- France -- Theatre since 1970, 1981 (Box 21)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby -- Since 1970 -- France -- Visual Artist since 1970, 1981 (Box 21)
  - D'Arschot, Ruby -- Since 1970 -- France -- Music since 1970, 1981 (Box 21)
  - Community Arts Organizations Report -- Jenneth Webster, 1977 (Box 21)
  - Spain -- The Situation of the Plastic Arts, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Netherlands -- Music in the Netherlands (Box 22)
  - Denmark -- the situation of Theatre, Music, Cinema and the Plastic Arts, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Norway -- the situation of the Plastic Arts, Theatre, Music, Literature and Cinema, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Sweden -- the situation of the Theatre, Music, Plastic Arts, Novelist and Cinema, 1970 (Box 22)
  - Finland -- Situation of the Arts in, 1970 (Box 22)
  - The Theater and Symphony Orchestras in France and French-speaking areas of Belgium and Switzerland -- Draft (French) (Box 22)
  - France -- Situation of the Composer, 1960 (Box 22)
  - France -- Situation of the Artist, 1960 (Box 22)
  - England -- Situation of the Composer, 1960 (Box 22)
  - England -- Situation of the Artists, 1960 (Box 22)
  - Germany -- Music in the Federal Republic of Germany (English), n.d. (Box 22)
  - Germany -- Music in the Federal Republic of Germany (French), n.d. (Box 22)
  - France -- Music in France, 1966 (Box 22)
  - England -- Situation of Music, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Great Britain -- the situation of the Theatre, 1968 (Box 22)
  - Switzerland -- Situation of the Theater and Music, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Spain -- Situation of the Theater, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Spain -- the Official School of Cinematography, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Spain -- the Situation of Music, 1969 (Box 22)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Impact of Price Increases on Ticket Demand for the Minnesota Orch., Apr 1976 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Washington DC Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the Seattle Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)
  - Eric Marder Associates -- A Study of the Performing Arts in the San Francisco Area, Jul 1972 (Box 23)